<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Critik blog</title>
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://blog.critik.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://blog.critik.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Critik</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How should you ask for feedback? 7 rules for better insights.</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2016/10/06/how-should-you-ask-for-feedback-7-rules-for-better-insights/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2016/10/06/how-should-you-ask-for-feedback-7-rules-for-better-insights/</id>
    <published>2016-10-06T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s one of the most common questions we hear from businesses. How do I ask my customers and employees for feedback?</p>
<p>Anyone can write an email that asks people to fill out a short survey. But when you appreciate that survey fatigue syndrome (‘SFS’ - don’t Google it, we coined it) is entrenched in a large proportion of your customer base, the real challenge is to cut through the noise and activate a response. </p>
<p><strong>Simply appealing to a sense of loyalty or offering a reward for feedback is not enough.</strong> Consumers are used to feeling manipulated by large corporates that they know don’t really care about them. Your business has to stand out or you risk making customers even more resistant to speaking up. </p>
<p>Appreciate that every request for feedback has a cost/ benefit association. If you ask for feedback well, you will create a culture of engagement and have to ask less often in the future. </p>
<p>If on the other hand you ask poorly, you will just reinforce to customers that feedback is annoying, gradually grinding away any willingness to speak up except in relation to the most negative of experiences. Unfortunately this is a space to which we have all become accustomed.</p>
<p>So what should you say to your customers and employees to elicit the highest rate of response? Simply put, you need to <strong>emphasise the personal nature and unique depth of relationship you have with your people.</strong></p>
<p>To put it in even simpler terms, the starting point is that human beings (you and me) are most real when having a face-to-face conversation with someone they like and trust. <strong>You need to create as close to this space as possible.</strong></p>
<p>Part of this is about having a good relationship with your customers in the first place. You can’t overcome months of bad customer service with one cheerful email. But how you ask is definitely important. Feedback is an emotional response more than an intellectual exercise. So if you ask in a way that makes people feel good they will respond more often and give you better feedback. </p>
<p><strong>Here are some top tips to help your customers and employees feel good about speaking up.</strong> These apply whether you ask by email, text, messaging app or other platform.</p>
<p><strong>1.    Be conversational</strong> -  Be professional but casual. People respond well to conversational, friendly language better than heavy prose. Just like having a coffee with your best friend.</p>
<p><strong>2.    Articulate a shared ‘why’</strong> - Why does this feedback matter to both you (the business) and the customer or employee? Be relatable. Better to give one real reason for collecting feedback than a spiel about ‘continuous improvement’. Your priority is to cut through survey fatigue, not to intellectually convince people about the value of feedback.</p>
<p><strong>3.    Use humour</strong> - A little lightness or self-deprecation can engender goodwill and better responses.</p>
<p><strong>4.    Think about what people want to hear</strong> - Address people by name (‘Hi Matt’, ‘Dear Sarah’) and don’t use the words that emphasise structure (survey, process, form etc). Structure is the enemy of free flowing conversation. Similarly don’t use overused catchphrases - (e.g. ‘your opinion matters’). Your customers will see straight through this.</p>
<p><strong>5.    Demonstrate how feedback can and will bring about change</strong> - Describe how feedback has led to improvement in the past. Identify one-two specific changes that have been made as a result of recent feedback. Even better throw in a short testimony - ‘last month in response to member/ name’s feedback we implemented change X’</p>
<p><strong>6.    Emphasise ‘recency’</strong> - People give feedback in response to emotional triggers and so are most inclined to give feedback about recent experiences. Tap into this by specifying a time period (e.g. “have you get any ideas about how we could have improved our service in the last week”).</p>
<p><strong>7.    Say thank you:</strong> Simple but critical. Make sure you thank people for their thoughts in advance.</p>
<p>Are you in the health space and want more intelligent feedback? Tune in to next week’s <a href="http://blog.critik.com/">blog</a> to find out which feedback tools are getting the best results for medical providers.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;It’s one of the most common questions we hear from businesses. How do I ask my customers and employees for feedback?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can wr
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why I don’t like giving feedback</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2016/08/26/why-I-dont-like-giving-feedback/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2016/08/26/why-I-dont-like-giving-feedback/</id>
    <published>2016-08-26T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Giving feedback is so little of the time about me.</p>
<p>First world problem. “Nobody’s listening to me, nobody cares about my pain, blah blah.” I get it, there are issues more critical than whether the café puts the wrong sauce on my vegan buckwheat wrap.</p>
<p>But let’s indulge for a moment and be honest about this issue. Because as customers we get feedback requests thrown at us all the time. I accept that businesses value my customer satisfaction even if cynically. But most of the time I still don’t want to give you feedback. And it’s not just me – in fact <a href="https://blog.productpains.com/why-you-don-t-give-feedback-2ed6a5778121#.eaqdudqm7" target="_blank" rel="external">49.7% of us don’t speak up when we have a frustrating product experience</a>.</p>
<p>So what’s with the discrepancy?</p>
<p>The truth is that I expect things to just work. I expect my coffee to be hot. I expect you to service my car correctly. I expect you to process my payment in time. And when everything is as I expect, you probably won’t hear from me through a feedback form or suggestion box.</p>
<p>When things don’t work; when I have an experience that doesn’t meet my expectations, it’s my loss. I’m the one whose trust was damaged. The social contract where I gave you my money and you promised to give me a ‘defined something’ in return. Well you didn’t give me that defined something!</p>
<p>When you ask for feedback afterwards, you’re asking me to give you even more trust and help you out. This is a big ask.</p>
<p><strong>It’s no wonder feedback is so hard to get.</strong></p>
<p>Breaking news - the circuit breaker to all this is a relationship. A relationship takes a contract (I pay; you give me coffee) into a higher domain. A relationship encourages me to be generous, to give you my trust a second time. And yes, a relationship enables me to forgive your mistake and see what really matters.</p>
<p>A better system to collect feedback or a juicier reward for my time will never offer the entire answer. You and your employees have to build real person-person connections with your customers.  It’s not personalising every email and knowing the name of my cat. I just want to be reminded that <strong>we’re two human beings solving a problem together</strong>. This sentiment is so rare these days. </p>
<p>Do this and I’ll invest far more in your business than just my feedback.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Giving feedback is so little of the time about me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First world problem. “Nobody’s listening to me, nobody cares about my pain, bla
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Feedback and gambling. Say what?</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2016/07/22/feedback-and-gambling-say-what/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2016/07/22/feedback-and-gambling-say-what/</id>
    <published>2016-07-22T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Getting customer feedback is like running a casino table. </p>
<p>You stack the odds too low and the players get rich off your generosity and leave you in the red. You stack the odds too high and the players don’t play. A public review forum is an example of the former. A ten-page survey is the latter.</p>
<p>So how do you set up an attractive game for both sides?</p>
<p>As a business, every customer you email a survey or ask for a positive review conducts a cost/benefit analysis of your request. They stack up their own time and effort against their personal satisfaction of speaking up.</p>
<p>They also consider the odds of being listened to, the value of a reward you might promise them and likelihood their feedback will result in actual improvement to your business.</p>
<p>The starting point is that <strong>customers perceive the odds as being weighted heavily against them</strong>. Customers are asked for feedback all the time and are biased about the house. Fair or not, customers exaggerate the costs and minimise the benefits. </p>
<p>The consequence as we all know is that it’s hard to get customers to speak up, especially to give neutral or positive feedback. If you are a business you have to work very hard to attract players to your table.</p>
<p>The fact is that many businesses concentrate so hard on trying to win the game (“what data do we need”) and forget they need customers to actually play.</p>
<p>It’s no surprise that customers find themselves wandering between tables wanting to play but never quite convinced any game is winnable. This is where the frustration and general malaise around giving feedback sets in.</p>
<p>At Critik, we are disrupting this process. Unlike many feedback platforms, we think the core question is not <strong>“what data do we need”</strong> but <strong>“how do we set up an attractive game?”</strong></p>
<p>So if your business is new to Critik, here are the golden rules we we think make a good game:</p>
<p>• <strong>Low effort wins every time.</strong> It doesn’t matter how much your customers love your business. Feedback must be easy. Must.</p>
<p>• <strong>Make the reward easier to get, not just larger.</strong> No one actually believes they are going to win the $10M jackpot on the slots.</p>
<p>• <strong>The game is as important as the win</strong>. Make giving feedback enjoyable and your customers will come back for another round.</p>
<p>• <strong>Don’t bank on customer generosity.</strong> Customers have a lot of other competing tables asking them to play. </p>
<p>The irony is that if you concentrate on setting up an attractive game, you will get the data and customer engagement you want. </p>
<p>At Critik we simply help you build a great game. <strong>Sign up and get a free 30 day trial</strong> at <a href="https://critik.com/" target="_blank" rel="external">critik.com</a></p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Getting customer feedback is like running a casino table. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You stack the odds too low and the players get rich off your generosity
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Critik is live</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2016/06/24/critik-is-live/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2016/06/24/critik-is-live/</id>
    <published>2016-06-24T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We’re here to revolutionise feedback.</p>
<p>Giving feedback should not be a process of clunky surveys and customers who are tempted along by the chance of a $100 reward.</p>
<p>Feedback should be about customers saying exactly what they want to say. And about businesses getting great value from honest customer sentiment.</p>
<p>So Critik is here to change the party.</p>
<p>We reckon feedback looks more like a conversation than a questionnaire.</p>
<p>Our vision is to make it as easy as possible for customers to say exactly what they want. Then taking that data and getting it directly and privately to businesses so they can keep creating the amazing products and services that we want.</p>
<p>If we had to describe ourselves in one sentence, we would say that we love the crowd but we reckon the relationship is better.</p>
<p>Sign up for free at <a href="https://critik.com" target="_blank" rel="external">critik.com</a> and tell us what you think. Start your business on a journey towards great customer feedback with a 30-day trial.</p>
<p>We want your feedback and we want to know how we can be even better.</p>
<p>In fact we want to be the best.</p>
<p>For you. Whether you are a customer or a business. We’re listening on Critik.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;We’re here to revolutionise feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving feedback should not be a process of clunky surveys and customers who are tempted alon
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Single or multi-channel feedback?</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2016/06/23/single-or-multi-channel-feedback/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2016/06/23/single-or-multi-channel-feedback/</id>
    <published>2016-06-23T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we pitch Critik to potential clients, we get one question 99% of the time.</p>
<p>“I’m already doing customer feedback, why do I need another channel”.  We reply “Because Critik is awesome”.</p>
<p>They agree, we make the sell and then we crack a round of drinks to celebrate.</p>
<p>If only it was that easy.</p>
<p>Changing the way people give feedback is the easy part. But changing the way that people get feedback is difficult. Especially at a time of excess in social media and public forums mixed in with live chat, email and of course the classic helpdesk.</p>
<p>So when we suggest throwing Critik into the mix, it’s understandable that businesses question why.</p>
<p>Now of course there are good reasons why. Critik is super easy for customers, it channels feedback out of the public domain and it gives you a bunch of analytics to help make use of your data.</p>
<p>But the next question is whether you adopt Critik as your only feedback channel. Or whether you deploy it alongside existing channels that your customers use to speak up.</p>
<p>If you can you should offer Critik as your only feedback channel, you should. Straight up.</p>
<p>In the same way that limiting choices is good for sales, <strong>focussing your feedback is likely to result in higher customer conversion</strong>. It’s a fact demonstrated by established research from <a href="https://faculty.washington.edu/jdb/345/345%20Articles/Iyengar%20%26%20Lepper%20(2000).pdf" target="_blank" rel="external">Columbia University</a>, email marketing campaigns and ice-cream flavours (who eats bubble-gum flavour ice cream anyway?).</p>
<p>So when should you offer Critik as part of a multi-channel strategy?</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Senior demographic:</strong> Whoever said mature customers don’t use mobiles! Try using Critik next to paper forms and compare the results.</li>
<li><strong>Established systems:</strong> Switching to Critik too much of a disruption to your customer service management? Setup is simple and Critik can be trialled without significant risk to your other channels.</li>
<li><strong>Personal context:</strong> Is face to face customer interaction a regular part of your business? Critik is awesome but there’s nothing better than encouraging in-person feedback.</li>
</ul>
<p>If you have an agile business, a Critik-only approach is the way to go. But if you need to, migrate your customers gradually.</p>
<p>Manage other communication through phone, email or social media, but listen to feedback on Critik. We guarantee your customers will respond.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;When we pitch Critik to potential clients, we get one question 99% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m already doing customer feedback, why do I nee
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to do amazing customer service Japanese style</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2016/04/27/customer-service-japanese-style/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2016/04/27/customer-service-japanese-style/</id>
    <published>2016-04-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some of our Critik team travelled to Japan recently. It’s hard not to be blown away by the incredible country, food and winter culture. But it’s even harder not to be attracted to the way Japanese people treat their guests.</p>
<p>The Japanese have a way of surprising you as to just how ‘guest-centric’ they are.  The hospitality plays out when you’re arriving at Narita airport, when you’re boarding the Shinkansen or when you ordering the best ever ramen at a local watering hole. It also plays out in local homes - staying at a local guesthouse is more akin to staying with a family friend than at a commercial hotel.</p>
<p>CX analyst Ryan Hart blogged recently about the Japanese culture of omotenashi – the ‘unobtrusive and respectful approach to guests that anticipates their needs, bestows respect and surprises them at every point in the service scenario’. Or in other words, ‘to entertain a guest wholeheartedly’. This national culture of empathy causes Japanese companies to have incredible customer service, despite a comparative lack of rigorous CX methodology in Japanese business practice. Check out Hart’s full blog <a href="https://www.forrester.com/ryan-hart" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>.</p>
<p>What this means for your business is that you don’t need a complicated, multi-channel, consultant designed customer service strategy to build your customer base! Instead, win trust and loyalty by simply treating your customers like honoured guests. This is not breaking news – it’s just recognising that relationships (not science or strategy) are still the real keys to building a great business.</p>
<p>The three fundamentals are to <strong>treat your customers like a good friend</strong>, to <strong>anticipate what your customers want</strong> and to have <strong>heart-to-heart conversations</strong> with your customers. We unashamedly think Critik is the best C2B communication channel out there to help you do all three. But whether you use Critik, email or the humble telegram, the priority is to replicate as close as possible a <em>personal friendship with your customers</em>.</p>
<p>So how to kick off your winning omotenashi style customer engagement? Don’t stress about getting your strategy right. Just find the best way to connect, be a really good person and make sure your employees do the same. The rest is up to your customers.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Some of our Critik team travelled to Japan recently. It’s hard not to be blown away by the incredible country, food and winter culture. B
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Creating loyalty</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/12/23/creating-loyalty-1/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/12/23/creating-loyalty-1/</id>
    <published>2015-12-23T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have said that customer loyalty is won by a bold vision, clearly articulated to customers and passionately followed through. We said that this, not a frequent shopper card, is the key to winning loyal customers to your business. Here are some practical tips to really build your customer fan club that will help your small/medium business!</p>
<p>One of the best ways to build customer loyalty is to have an effective customer feedback mechanism. Asking for and listening to feedback is not just about resolving complaints or improving your business (although these things are great), it is about opening the communication loop from your customers to you and back again. If you encourage the conversation between you, your employees and your customers, this will allow you to articulate your vision, build trust and demonstrate how passionate you are about the story you are creating. Sound silly? Trust us, your customers and your employees want to see there is a narrative behind your brand. Giving feedback is the main way they express their loyalty to you. Listening to their feedback is the main way you can show your loyalty back.</p>
<p>We do not just mean a feedback box on the front counter or a random email address - we mean a quick and simple-to-use system <em>that your customers know you are listening to</em>. There’s nothing worse for your brand integrity than to ask for feedback and not actually listen to what your customers are saying.</p>
<p>So what can an effective feedback system look like? That’s where a tool like Critik comes in. Launching in 2016, Critik will make it easy for you to build loyalty by encouraging customers to speak their mind directly to you and your team and just as easy for you to respond and get the conversation going. Watch this space!</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;We have said that customer loyalty is won by a bold vision, clearly articulated to customers and passionately followed through. We said t
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Loyalty - is it just about the coffee card?</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/11/30/loyalty-is-it-just-about-the-coffee-card/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/11/30/loyalty-is-it-just-about-the-coffee-card/</id>
    <published>2015-11-30T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Loyalty is a word that gets thrown around a lot in the marketing and customer experience space. The idea that customers will come back repeatedly to purchase products or services. Or, at a deeper level, that customers will have an affinity with what your brand represents, whether because of the quality of your product, the appeal of your culture, or trust in your people.</p>
<p>But what exactly is loyalty and how do businesses create it? Is it, as the title suggests, about enticing customer retention via rewards attached to frequent purchases, or is it more than this? And what lessons are there for small to medium businesses wanting to retain customers through loyalty schemes?</p>
<p>First point - for most people loyalty is not about wanting free stuff. <strong>Loyalty is emotional</strong> and starts with what Simon Sinek has coined ‘the question of why’. Check out his TED talk below if you haven’t seen it. To summarise, it is the idea that successful people and companies know what purpose, cause or belief inspires them to do what they do.  It is the idea that people are looking to catch hold of a vision, including when they engage with a business.</p>
<div class="video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/qp0HIF3SfI4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
<p>Apple is the great example of a brand that has mastered loyalty by knowing its why. The technical and design features of the newest iPhone are just one part of the picture. As we know from the images of dedicated fans lining up for product releases, there is an idea associated with the Apple brand that grabs people. This idea is ‘challenging the status quo’. Starting with Steve Jobs and continuing today, Apple is adept at communicating and embodying this vision in everything it does. Apple’s products, its employee culture, its shopfronts - they all reflect this idea of challenging normal. And this idea has engendered a level of extreme loyalty.</p>
<p>For small enterprises – think tradespeople, cafe owners, family businesses and local grocers – admittedly your ‘why’ might seem a whole less grand than ‘challenging the status quo’. This is ok. A vision does not necessarily have to be unique or world changing; <em>it simply has to take your customers on a journey beyond encouraging them to buy more</em>. In other words, it has to inspire them.</p>
<p>Second point - <strong>loyalty is trust</strong>. In the business context, it is when a customer believes that a brand will genuinely hold itself accountable to its vision – that it will follow through on its promises. Accordingly, loyalty is created and reinforced by a business consistently demonstrating that it is achieving its why. In reality, it is rare to see this done well.</p>
<p>Consider how many businesses out there have visions that sit on mission statements and don’t actually impact the way they run day-to-day operations. Or consider businesses that market their vision where there is clearly no way they can follow through. Adopting a signboard that states “100% satisfaction every time” feels like a marketing ploy. Advertising the promise of “selling the best coffee in Sydney” seems like a good idea but in reality is unsustainable, even for the best barista. To the customer these visions are nearly impossible to prove and just a little unbelievable. So whilst they might have some marketing value, they do not necessarily create loyalty.</p>
<p>Note that the problem here is not the vision; it is the execution of the vision. In the first scenario, creating loyalty might be ensuring your business provides a great service and then following up in person to determine whether the job met your customer’s expectations. It could be providing an opportunity for the customer to provide feedback and then resolving any complaints beyond their expectations. This will demonstrate your vision far more powerfully than a slogan on the side of a van! And taking the second scenario – perhaps it is about telling your customers the story of your coffee, how it was picked, when it was roasted and why it is so good. Perhaps it is about asking your customers how their coffee was when they visit next time. More than anything, it is probably about remembering their name and building a personal relationship. If you start to engage your customers even just a little, you will probably get them thinking your coffee is the best in town, even if it isn’t.</p>
<p>So loyalty cards? We think they’re not quite what they are made out to be. Loyalty cards do not communicate a vision and they do not build trust. Whilst rewarding your customers for their business is not a bad idea per se (who would turn down a free 10th coffee!), perhaps there is potential for businesses to encourage customer engagement and create powerful brand allegiance by actually turning the loyalty card concept on its head.</p>
<p>So how to create real lasting customer loyalty? We’ll give you the answer in our next post.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Loyalty is a word that gets thrown around a lot in the marketing and customer experience space. The idea that customers will come back re
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A birthday message for email</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/11/12/a-birthday-message-for-email/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/11/12/a-birthday-message-for-email/</id>
    <published>2015-11-12T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Email turned 44 years old last month. That’s right, the first email was sent in 1971. And 22 years after it launched to the mainstream public, email is kicking goals as the most popular form of communication between customers and businesses.</p>
<p>So email has to be doing something right, right? Because despite all its younger competitors&mdash;the 20 year old search engines and the barely adolescent social media platforms&mdash;email is leading the way. And in the customer experience space, the unassuming veteran of digital communications is still capturing attention as the feedback platform of first choice.</p>
<p>What about the data? Microsoft recently released its 2015 report into multichannel customer service in the United Kingdom. You can check out the full report <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-gb/dynamics/multichannel-customer-service" target="_blank" rel="external">here</a>. Let’s agree that this study is broadly representative of customer engagement in a robust modern economy with a vibrant consumer sector - i.e. Britain has some lessons for the rest of us.</p>
<p>For those of you who aren’t consumer experience geeks like us, here are the basics.</p>
<p>82% of customers regularly use email to engage a brand. This compares to 72% who jump on the telephone, 58% on live chat, 46% on Google or other search engine, 18% on social media and 14% who use online forums.</p>
<p>When it comes to first preference, the contrast is even starker. 96% of customers would prefer to use email, telephone or live chat, with a nearly even split between all three. And although an approximate <a href="http://mashable.com/2014/02/13/linkedin-social-media-study/#kXvLyPP37sq3" target="_blank" rel="external">81% of small and medium businesses use social media</a> as marketing strategy, only a mere 2% of customers favour social media as the best way to engage a brand. Stacked up against the plethora of social media and messaging platforms out there, why does email stand out?</p>
<p>A few thoughts. First, email promises direct contact with the decision maker, or at the minimum, a <strong>real person</strong>. This is critical, and it helps to explain why the telephone and live chat are so popular too. The idea of connecting with a real human being who, for a moment of their day is listening to just you, is an incredibly powerful motivator. This is especially valuable when you are upset, frustrated or thrilled by an experience - all common emotions at play when customers are motivated enough by a brand experience to provide feedback.</p>
<p>Two, <strong>email is a reliable, consistent and universal interface</strong>. Email is predictable. And that’s what customers want. Given the little time that customers are prepared to engage with a business to provide feedback, the offering of multiple social media platforms and bespoke business apps just don’t cut it. Keeping in mind that effort is still the biggest disincentive to customer feedback, email is just easy. Every business has an email address, it’s accessible through the same inbox every time and there is a nearly 100% chance that your message will get in front of the person you intend. Ubiquitousness is not a guarantee of great customer service but it is a good start.</p>
<p>And finally three, <strong>email balances formality and ease just nicely</strong>. In the same way that writing a letter offers the innate satisfaction of having told your story on paper, email echoes this. It guarantees a certain level of respect between writer and reader in a way that a tweet or a comment box blurb often can’t. In the age of information overshare, the privacy of email also gives our stories just that little bit more credibility than posting our rants online. </p>
<p>With 75% of customers starting their engagement with a business on their computer and 25% on a mobile, email is the first choice for brand engagement. That is, until we see something else come into the marketplace that can compete for customer attention in the same ubiquitous way that email does (watch this space!).</p>
<p>So email may not be the only answer for long, but for now it has some key takeaways for any business that cares about its customers.</p>
<p>Happy birthday email.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Email turned 44 years old last month. That’s right, the first email was sent in 1971. And 22 years after it launched to the mainstream pu
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Characteristics of great customer service</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/11/03/characteristics-of-great-customer-service/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/11/03/characteristics-of-great-customer-service/</id>
    <published>2015-11-03T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What do organisations that offer great customer service look like? Some customer experience gold from US based customer service experts <a href="http://www.taketheirbreathaway.com/customer-insight/keeping-up-with-customer-insight/" target="_blank" rel="external">Chip Bell and John Patterson</a>.</p>
<p>The best organisations:</p>
<ul>
<li>Involve in the customer intelligence gathering process those people who can make or influence substantive changes based on what is learned.</li>
<li>Create sincere rapport with customers that will cause them to want to be honest.</li>
<li>Convince customers that their input will honestly matter.</li>
<li>Outline ways customers will be able to determine how the truth provided will be employed.</li>
<li>Show no defensiveness when customers provide feedback that is painful, inaccurate or even unfair.</li>
<li>Listen to learn – not to defend, teach or make a point.</li>
<li>Never make promises to customers they cannot or do not keep.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;What do organisations that offer great customer service look like? Some customer experience gold from US based customer service experts &lt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How (not) to manage customer complaints</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/30/how-not-to-manage-customer-complaints/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/30/how-not-to-manage-customer-complaints/</id>
    <published>2015-10-30T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this week, a popular Australian hotel chain got some less-than-positive media coverage for allegedly manipulating its TripAdvisor ratings. Emails surfaced showing it had bribed customers to remove negative feedback, in one instance offering a $100 discount to a guest for delete a bad review. The hotel was also accused of masking negative reviews by ensuring guests who complained did not receive TripAdvisor feedback forms.</p>
<p>Now that the allegations have surfaced, it clearly looks bad for the hotel. Selectively soliciting positive reviews is against TripAdvisor’s terms of use and offering incentives for good feedback is considered fraudulent.</p>
<p>But perhaps the hotel’s biggest mistake was failing to see the absolute gift that its complaining guests were offering. By taking a negative attitude towards negative feedback, the hotel not only compounded a bad outcome but missed out on a good one. Consider the situation if the hotel had decided to positively handle these negative TripAdvisor ratings and offer an exceptional level of customer service to its complaining guests:</p>
<ul>
<li>Customers are remarkably forgiving of a brand when they experience great service - the majority would have returned in the future.</li>
<li>Those once complaining guests would have become brand ambassadors to family and friends.</li>
<li>Potential guests would see that the hotel genuinely acted on feedback and more would have been forthcoming in the future, giving the company more opportunities to improve service and meet customer needs.</li>
<li>The public would have seen the hotel as a place that went beyond expectations for its guests, leading to an increase in sales and profitability.</li>
<li>Employees would have felt part of an enterprise that cared about its people, both customers and staff. Happier staff means better performance, decreased turnover and lower costs.</li>
<li>The hotel would have encouraged an upwardly positive cycle of great customer service, repeat business, increased feedback and more opportunities to offer even better service in the future.</li>
</ul>
<p>The irony is that had they received great customer service in response to their complaints, the same complaining guests may have offered additional positive reviews in lieu of their negative ones – the very outcome the hotel was looking for.</p>
<p>Online ratings and reviews can seem to overwhelm a business’s customer service department, especially in high volume sectors like accommodation and hospitality. But rather than trying to suppress it, using negative feedback to positively market your business will actually be beneficial for your bottom line.</p>
<p>Now that makes good business sense.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Earlier this week, a popular Australian hotel chain got some less-than-positive media coverage for allegedly manipulating its TripAdvisor
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Are customers dishonest?</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/27/are-customers-dishonest/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/27/are-customers-dishonest/</id>
    <published>2015-10-27T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just in case you’re not following the news, Amazon recently filed a claim in Seattle, <a href="http://news.sky.com/story/1571496/amazon-sues-1114-fake-reviewers-for-hire" target="_blank" rel="external">suing 1,114 people</a> for allegedly posting fake reviews on its website.</p>
<p>According to Amazon, the defendants were gaming the system by offering to provide reviews for money through the popular ‘micro-services’ broker Fiverr.com. Reviewers promised to write positive reviews of products, which affected the integrity of the Amazon customer review system and according to Amazon, had caused ‘an unhealthy ecosystem to develop to supply reviews in exchange for payment’.</p>
<p>This was systematic cheating with a clear motivation – payment for a service. But it begs the question: how many customers are regularly dishonest in their business transactions?  Now we’re not talking about theft or stealing or daylight robbery – naturally, a small proportion of the community are that way inclined. We are talking about the white lies, the small acts of deceit that over time cost businesses real money. Think of returning a product under a false pretext; or attempting to claim a store-offered incentive without purchasing the required item; or making a false complaint about a meal to claim a discount next time. Or the big one: posting an exaggeratedly nasty review online simply to punish a business or force a refund.</p>
<p>Statistics say that 1-4% of customers will systematically try to cheat. But since the arrival of online review platforms, the line between cheating and expressing your strong dissatisfaction online has blurred. So this statistic may be higher if we include the vocal minority who intentionally manipulate businesses through posting extremely bad reviews. Or those who are paid to post fake reviews. Yelp, for example, estimates that 16% of restaurant reviews are fraudulent.</p>
<p>For Amazon, suing 1,114 people was a strategic move to protect their credibility. For most other businesses, the problem is preventing actual losses while managing image. How do you avoid blaming an honest customer? How do you treat a dishonest customer without descending into an embarrassing argument in person or online? And how does this all look to honest customers watching on?</p>
<p>This is a big topic but here are three ideas for businesses to start with:</p>
<ol>
<li><p><strong>Strategically manage the incentives to cheat</strong>. Like anyone, customers are economic actors who respond to incentives and disincentives. If it’s easier and more profitable to do they right thing, they probably will. So make it easy for your good customers to provide feedback, return products and resolve complaints. This will make it harder for your dishonest customers to have an impact. And, it will be good for your bottom line.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Take it offline</strong> (not literally). If somebody has a genuine complaint, they won’t mind making the conversation private - whether in person, by email or other channels. Provided you are willing to consider their issue and give it the attention they think it deserves, most customers are willing to forgive transgressions if they feel cared about. Nobody benefits from public confrontations and online rants. Absolutely nobody.</p>
</li>
<li><p><strong>Be the higher person</strong>. Like with any customer who engages with your business, responding to a dishonest customer is an opportunity to build your brand. Treat a dishonest customer so well that everyone watching on cannot help but be impressed by your superior customer service - and you will win the loyalty of many more good customers. You may even convert the bad one.</p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Just in case you’re not following the news, Amazon recently filed a claim in Seattle, &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.sky.com/story/1571496/amazon-s
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The cost of not listening in</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/23/the-cost-of-not-listening-in/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/23/the-cost-of-not-listening-in/</id>
    <published>2015-10-23T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is the cost you pay as a business owner for not loving your customer feedback? It could be more than you think.</p>
<p>Customers are actually remarkably forgiving of businesses with promises that are not initially delivered, as long as businesses respond to customers effectively, make good on their product or service promises and demonstrate that matters are improving. Not only might they forgive you but they might like you even more afterwards. Responding to a customer’s feedback is an opportunity to show how good you really are - a chance to win (or reinforce) the ongoing loyalty of a happy customer. For you, the business owner, it could be marketing gold.</p>
<p>Gaining a new customer can cost <a href="https://blog.kissmetrics.com/retaining-customers/" target="_blank" rel="external">seven times more</a> than retaining an existing one. It’s worth keeping your tribe happy because customer churn is expensive and has a strong negative effect on your brand. Or to put it another way, feedback is an asset with an actual dollar value. Every dollar of time you spend on listening to your customers is a dollar you don’t have to spend on marketing.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.destinationcrm.com/Articles/Editorial/Magazine-Features/Launching-Profits-with-Customer-Loyalty-41678.aspx" target="_blank" rel="external">Statistics say</a> that retail businesses out there lose 25-40% of their core customers every year. Crazy numbers! It means you retail business owners have to replace up to 40% of your customers every year just to stay on top! Between one quarter and one half of your marketing efforts are used to maintain your existing customer base.</p>
<p>If it costs you five times more to gain a new customer and you lose up to 40% of your customers each year, then surely you want to be putting as many of your dollars into effective feedback management as possible. And the additional costs of rewarding customers for good feedback or compensating them for unsatisfactory products or services will undoubtedly be offset by the savings in your marketing budget.</p>
<p>So what is the cost of not listening in? Ask yourself: how many thousands of dollars worth of customers can I keep with good feedback management?</p>
<p>Listening in to your customers might just be the best marketing tool you have.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;What is the cost you pay as a business owner for not loving your customer feedback? It could be more than you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers are
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Survey fatigue - part 2</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/20/survey-fatigue-part-2/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/20/survey-fatigue-part-2/</id>
    <published>2015-10-20T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Is there a feedback sweet spot where customers and companies both can win?</p>
<p>Surveys are not the sweet spot. Businesses want to capture a high volume of data per customer to meet specific information requirements. They don’t get much of a response. 20-30% response rates are considered a remarkable success while most surveys garner less than 10%.</p>
<p>Reviews in online public forums may be closer to that sweet spot. The customer gets to write on their terms. They can say what they want without wading through five pages of checkboxes or detailed questions not related to their experience. For companies, this presents some problems. Quantity and specificity of information is a big challenge.  Reviews are often polarised and less than objective. Even when there are enough data points to draw valid conclusions, feedback ends up scattered across multiple forums, leaving the company to collect and aggregate the data.</p>
<p>The biggest challenge here for companies is responding to customer reviews to manage their online presence. These days, no company or organisation is immune from the push to create a review profile at the insistence of a third party.  Once created, it is the vocal negative minority that shout the loudest. Having to placate the 5% in the name of demonstrating good customer service comes at the cost of delivering better service to the other 95%. And most of the 95% are generally satisfied with their experiences, they just don’t say it. It is no surprise then that companies end up feeling manipulated by the very services acquired to help them engage better with their customers.</p>
<p>So what is the answer?</p>
<p>Feedback is obviously still useful to companies. Author for The Australian, Diedre Macken <a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/arts/review/customer-feedback-surveys-its-not-about-you-its-about-them/story-fn9n8gph-1227531763850" target="_blank" rel="external">notes</a>, ‘It’s cheap market information…and smart companies combine the feedback with data they have from your online interactions with them. Analytics are worth a lot more to them than to you.’ Feedback helps companies reconstruct themselves, alter their marketing strategies and bring new products and services to market. Feedback should be collected in a way that does not pit the interests of the company (getting the information it wants) against those of the customer (saying what they want).</p>
<p>Diedre says, ‘It’s time to even the score and start answering the questions we’d like to see on surveys.’ We agree - it is time for customers to start saying what they want. But the answer is not exchanging surveys for more public rants.</p>
<p>In the good old days the customer was able to have a conversation with the business owner over the counter. In 2015, we think the answer is to provide a clear channel between the customer and the company in the digital space. One that is direct, protected and easier to access than a call centre or generic customer service inbox. Make it easier for customers to speak, and easier for companies to listen. And then get out of their way!</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Is there a feedback sweet spot where customers and companies both can win?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surveys are not the sweet spot. Businesses want to capt
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Survey fatigue - part 1</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/16/survey-fatigue-part-1/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/16/survey-fatigue-part-1/</id>
    <published>2015-10-16T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Acknowledgements to Deidre Macken for her piece on <a href="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/arts/review/customer-feedback-surveys-its-not-about-you-its-about-them/story-fn9n8gph-1227531763850" target="_blank" rel="external">Survey Fatigue</a> for the Weekend Australian, September 19, 2015.</p>
<p>Diedre is spot on about the frustrations of survey-based feedback; the model cannot be escaped when it comes to online commerce. She writes:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>‘It’s easy to get lured into providing customer feedback. It makes you feel important.  It’s a way of getting frustrations out of your system. And there’s always the vague hope that at the end of the 10 pages of questions, a jackpot will ring and you’ll be off to Europe on an all expenses paid holiday.</p>
<p>But many of us are getting survey fatigue. Yes, that’s an expression in marketing circles but it’s also how you feel when you get to the second page of a feedback form and start thinking, “this is not about me anymore”.’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There are some common motivations that make us, the customers, want to provide feedback. Diedre gives us three:</p>
<ol>
<li>It makes you feel important and validated.</li>
<li>It’s a way of getting frustrations out of your system.</li>
<li>For many of us, the promise of a reward is a small but real factor at play.</li>
</ol>
<p>We add a fourth motivation: feedback is often aimed at solving a problem for yourself or for the company you’re speaking to. And for a small minority there is a fifth category: speaking up out of the completely altruistic desire to provide useful feedback to a stranger, be they the owner of the company or a member of the public. Call us cynical, but we think popular online review platforms owe their success to peoples’ deep-seated desires for validation and not their altruistic tendencies.</p>
<p>Diedre identifies a key challenge – the imbalance between the customer’s motivations and the company’s desire for information:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>‘If you get to the second page of a feedback form, chances are that you are being asked to do the company’s market research, provide a performance rating for customer staff, redesign a website, contribute a testimonial to its advertising or, what’s worst, set yourself up for another selling opportunity from the company.’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But is it possible to find that sweet spot where both customers and companies feel they are getting a good deal from the exchange? Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Acknowledgements to Deidre Macken for her piece on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theaustralian.com.au/arts/review/customer-feedback-surveys-its-not
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A solution to the challenge of collecting feedback - part 2</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/13/a-solution-part-2/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/13/a-solution-part-2/</id>
    <published>2015-10-13T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In our <a href="/2015/10/10/a-solution-part-1/" title="last post">last post</a>, we began to discuss a solution to the challenge businesses face of collecting feedback from their customers. We think the solution looks something like the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Efficient</strong>: The solution recognises that customers often have an immediate snippet of information to share that is worth not more than a moment of their time.  And it recognises that business owners are busy, very busy.</li>
<li><strong>Simple</strong>: The solution encourages customer contribution by virtue of simple functionality, an enjoyable interface and the promise of creating genuine value.</li>
<li><strong>Direct</strong>: The solution guarantees a direct connection with business owners and/or customer service managers.  The customer should be able to trust that the person up the line who needs to know will find out.  The business should be able to trust that feedback is being fed up the line to the right decision makers.</li>
<li><strong>Private</strong>: The solution enables customers and businesses to keep feedback discreet.  And if it enables sharing for a wider audience, it does so in a way that protects privacy and does not unreasonably manipulate other parties in the exchange.</li>
<li><strong>Anonymous</strong>: The solution provides customers the choice whether to identify themselves. For those instances of potential embarrassment or where reputation may be at stake. The solution needs to do this whilst protecting businesses from anonymous spam feedback.</li>
<li><strong>Manageable</strong>: The solution makes it easy for businesses to respond to customers and for both customers and businesses to develop and track an ongoing conversation</li>
<li><strong>Evaluative</strong>:  The solution offers value-added analysis for businesses. It makes use of the feedback data and returns simple business intelligence.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are two other features that would make the solution really click. A feedback system needs to appreciate that customers suffer from information saturation and a lack of time. If we are to encourage customers to provide feedback on their terms, we need it to be <strong>universal</strong> and <strong>accessible</strong>. A common platform that is usable anytime, anywhere, in relation to any commercial, not-for-profit or government entity. It has to stand alone and be readily usable.</p>
<p>Sound refreshing? We certainly think so, enough to give up our day jobs and make it happen for you.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&quot;/2015/10/10/a-solution-part-1/&quot; title=&quot;last post&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;, we began to discuss a solution to the challenge business
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A solution to the challenge of collecting feedback - part 1</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/10/a-solution-part-1/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/10/a-solution-part-1/</id>
    <published>2015-10-10T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The objectives are clear: customers want to be heard, and businesses want the insights that will shape the way they operate in the future. If we can connect the two, we will increase customer satisfaction, fix problems, increase responsiveness to changing market conditions and ultimately boost revenue.</p>
<p>As we mentioned in a <a href="/2015/10/07/why-people-dont-leave-feedback/" title="previous post">previous post</a>, the typical barriers for customers are effort, lack of access, embarrassment, defeatism, desiring to be the ‘nice guy’, personal reputation, and the partial responsibility factor. The barriers for businesses are obstructed communication channels, lack of amplification to decision makers, the difficulty of sending quick and effective responses, and capturing and analysing feedback to get maximum utility from the data.</p>
<p>Any solution needs to overcome the barriers on both sides of the equation. We need a tool that is attractive to use for both customers and for businesses. Customers should not have to jump through hoops or feel they are being manipulated into providing fodder for marketing research. And businesses should feel able to manage customer relationships simply and on their own terms, not because they feel forced into a corner. In our next post we’ll detail what we think that solution should look like.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The objectives are clear: customers want to be heard, and businesses want the insights that will shape the way they operate in the future
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What businesses want</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/08/what-businesses-want/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/08/what-businesses-want/</id>
    <published>2015-10-08T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The second problem: capturing customer feedback and presenting it to businesses in a way that is easily consumable, useful for business improvement and leads to further engagement between the customer and the business.</p>
<p>Time–poor business owners and service managers cannot best manage customer relationships when engagement is spread across numerous domains, let alone make great use of the data that results. Responding to email, managing Facebook and Twitter posts, answering negative Yelp reviews, gathering survey data, answering phone calls, etc. The challenge is exaggerated for small business owners without the resources or staff to purchase and implement proper systems.</p>
<p>There are two aspects to this problem – how do we create a feedback system that makes it as easy as possible for businesses to manage customer engagement? And how does the system quickly tell businesses exactly what they want to know? Let’s remember that this is not simply a matter of asking targeted questions. We can see from experience that surveys are not the answer. With all the market research requests we are bombarded with in 2015, survey response is low and survey fatigue is high – consider your own response to the last email survey request you received.</p>
<p>Getting the data is not necessarily found in a 5 page, in–depth market research analysis paper either. Certainly not for a business that wants regular informative updates on its operating environment. We are talking about regular current data.  And we mean current; data that can be interpreted as easily as checking the news. Information telling the business exactly what they need to know so they can take immediate action steps and create meaningful change.</p>
<p>We at Critik think there are four features to recognise if a feedback platform is going to be attractive to businesses.  In simple terms, the system needs to guarantee the following:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Communication</strong>: Feedback needs to be able to reach the intended recipient(s).</li>
<li><strong>Amplification</strong>: Feedback needs to be able to be shared at each level of decision–making; from customer service at an operational level to strategic vision planning by senior management.</li>
<li><strong>Response–ability</strong>: Feedback needs to be easy to respond to.  And we mean as easy and quick as sending an SMS.</li>
<li><strong>Capture and Analysis</strong>: Feedback needs to be properly captured, with aggregated relevant data presented back to the business.</li>
</ol>
<p>The solution? That’s in our next post.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;The second problem: capturing customer feedback and presenting it to businesses in a way that is easily consumable, useful for business i
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Why people don&#39;t leave feedback</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/07/why-people-dont-leave-feedback/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/07/why-people-dont-leave-feedback/</id>
    <published>2015-10-07T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are seven simple but significant barriers that stop consumers speaking up:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>The Effort Factor</strong>: Customers want to provide feedback but ultimately cannot be bothered. Good intentions fail because it all just feels a bit exhausting.</li>
<li><strong>The Lack of Access Factor</strong>: Customers are dissuaded by a lack of easily apparent ways to provide feedback.  Conversely, they feel they have no guarantee it will be passed to the intended recipient.</li>
<li><strong>The Embarrassment Factor</strong>: Customers do not want to complain because of potential embarrassment to themselves or others.</li>
<li><strong>The Defeatist Factor</strong>: Customers believe that their feedback is unlikely to lead to change, so do not speak up.</li>
<li><strong>The Nice Guy Factor</strong>: Customers consider giving feedback but then self–talk, convincing themselves not to report a ‘minor infraction’.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Reputation Factor</strong>: Customers fear actual damage to their personal reputation or the relationship, especially where they rely on goodwill.</li>
<li><strong>The Partial Responsibility Factor</strong>: Customers anticipate lack of action and/or retribution due to partial responsibility, even though they have a valid complaint.</li>
</ol>
<p>At Critik we are losing sleep about how to overcome these barriers. We’ll let you know when we have the solution!</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;There are seven simple but significant barriers that stop consumers speaking up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Effort Factor&lt;/strong&gt;: Custome
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>What customers want</title>
    <link href="http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/06/what-customers-want/"/>
    <id>http://blog.critik.com/2015/10/06/what-customers-want/</id>
    <published>2015-10-06T00:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-10-06T02:39:43.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let’s face it – consumers are presented with constant opportunities to provide feedback. This is not a new challenge and the marketplace is saturated with options, both digital and old–school. Businesses and other organisations supplement feedback forms, surveys and focus groups with social media monitoring, website usability testing, community review boards, individually tailored mobile application and web–based market research platforms. To name a few in the digital domain – Yelp, TripAdvisor, Zomato, SurveyMonkey, UserVoice, Feedbackify, Kampyle, OpinionLab, IdeaScale, Yomstar, Satmetrix. The list goes on…</p>
<p>So why Critik? Do customers need another option to get their voices out there to the people that really want to know? We as customers are constantly bombarded with opportunities to tell businesses what we think. Survey forms abound and nearly every online booking, be it for flights, hotels or dinner out, involves some a request to contribute feedback. Despite the most plentiful existence of feedback tools ever, consistent customer engagement is still low.  No tool out there comprehensively alleviates the barriers that prevent an average 75% percent of consumers from providing feedback.  Statistics suggest that survey response is often as little as two percent. Even the current market leader in online surveys claims that a highly successful response rate is in the realm of 20–30%.</p>
<p>So that’s the first problem, getting customers to speak up. This is about both quantity (regular consistent engagement) and quality (a healthy ratio of insightful feedback to general rants!). And for us at Critik, we see this as simply a question of customer motivation; how do we unlock what the customer already wants to say?</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;Let’s face it – consumers are presented with constant opportunities to provide feedback. This is not a new challenge and the marketplace 
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
